Maggie Banker

503-502-8385 • maggiebanker@gmail.com

PROPERTY MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL

Forward thinking property management professional with eight years' experience. Exceptional provider of customer service and team leadership as evidenced by consistent history of revenue growth and NOI improvements. Ability to increase property visibility and drive traffic. Exceptional influencer - able to identify what motivates individuals and how to persuade them. Highly capable of analyzing, identifying and forecasting financial and leasing trends leading to more productive efforts. Hold valid Oregon property manager's license.

KEY SKILLS AND ABILITIES

- Licensed Property Manager
- Property Management & Leasing
- Fair Housing Laws
- Executive Leadership
- Administrative Management
- Tenant Relations

- Staff Supervision & Training
- Vendor Management
- Capital Improvements
- Strategic Planning
- Budget Development and Forecasting
- Process Improvements

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bluestone & Hockley Real Estate Services, Portland, OR

Residential Property Management Supervisor

2009 - Present

Manage leasing, tenant relations and maintenance for 1200 multifamily units and 300 single family homes. Supervise an office staff of ten employees and indirectly manage approximately 30 site staff. Assist with tenant relations and client relations as necessary to resolve open issues. Close single family house accounts and work closely with business development manager to attract new multi-family accounts. Recruit, hire and train employees; delegate and empower them to manage and be held accountable for daily operations of their respective departments. Present monthly training classes for staff and site personnel to ensure compliance with fair housing laws and corporate marketing and customer service policies. Prepare and implement annual department budget and business plan to provide operational insight to corporate management. Implement policies and procedures in order to meet corporate mandated goals.

Highlighted Accomplishments

- Selected to serve on corporate management team
- Increased client NOI across multiple properties
- Maintained a department portfolio vacancy rate under 3% for all of 2010
- Improved lease through rate by repositioning distressed properties
- Worked closely with attorneys and financial institutions as a receiver for properties in foreclosure
- Implemented staff training which resulted in dramatically improved customer service scores from residents

Bluestone & Hockley Real Estate Services, Portland, OR

2007 - 2009

Property Manager

Directed the duties of 13 staff members in managing 12 apartment buildings for various clients. Ensured tenant satisfaction by providing superior customer service and attending to maintenance needs in a timely manner. Oversaw rent collection policies and procedures to ensure all monies due were paid. Worked with late payers to try and reach a mutually beneficial outcome; referred tenants to collectors and attorneys when this was not possible. Performed yearly tenant inspections to protect owners' interests and identify issues in need of resolution. Advocated a proactive approach to maintenance and negotiated with vendors to contain maintenance costs. Planned, placed for bid and supervised the construction and completion of capital improvement projects. Created monthly management and financial reports to increase owner and corporate visibility into property operations. Prepared and implemented annual property budgets.

Highlighted Accomplishments

- Reduced maintenance costs by addressing small issues before they became larger and more costly to remedy
- Improved customer service, as evidenced by steady/increasing leasing renewals
- Promoted to Supervisor after exceeding budget and performance expectations

Alpine Property Management, Portland, OR

2004 - 2006

Tenant/Owner Relations & Business Development

Visible as the face of the company to tenants, real estate brokers and new property owners. Offered exceptional customer service while addressing the needs of three unique constituencies. Worked closely with internal leasing agents to address tenant concerns prior to move and persuade them to sign a lease. Provided daily reports to current property owners on the status of lease through rates, rent collection, pending vacancies, and maintenance needs. Conceived and implemented a variety of marketing strategies to drive traffic to available units.

Highlighted Accomplishments

Closed multiple deals to manage properties for new clients, resulting in the firm doubling in size

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Licensed Property Manager # 200511338, Oregon Real Estate Agency
- Certified Property Manager Candidate, Institute of Real Estate Management

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

- Commercial Association of Realtors
- Portland Metro Multifamily Housing Association

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, Portland State University, Portland, OR